Register of the Swarthmore College collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Swarthmore College collection
1911-1982
86027
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes (2.8 linear feet)
The Swarthmore College collection consists largely of pamphlets and other printed matter, arranged by subject. The preponderance of the materials relate to World War I; the Spanish Civil War; the espionage case of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg and Martin Sobell; and issues of world peace and disarmament. The Spanish Civil War items mainly pertain to organizations in the United States and elsewhere that were engaged in fundraising and publicity efforts on behalf of the Spanish Republic.
Arrangement Statement
The collection is organized into 3 series: Pamphlets, serial issues, leaflets and clippings; Miscellaneous printed matter; and Photographs.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Swarthmore College collection consists largely of pamphlets and other printed matter, arranged by subject. The preponderance of the materials relate to World War I; the Spanish Civil War; the espionage case of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg and Martin Sobell; and issues of world peace and disarmament. The Spanish Civil War items mainly pertain to organizations in the United States and elsewhere that were engaged in fundraising and publicity efforts on behalf of the Spanish Republic.
The collection also contains a smaller number of publications pertaining to a variety of subjects, including desegregation, East and West Germany, and the Vietnam War. All the materials in the collection were sent to the archives by Swarthmore College, and were determined either to be duplicates or to not be suitable for inclusion in the Swarthmore College Peace Collection.
Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953.; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953.; Sobell, Morton.; Swarthmore College.; Civil rights--United States.; Disarmament.; Espionage, Russian--United States.; Jews--Germany.; National socialism.; Peace.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Pamphlets, serial issues, leaflets, and clippings, 1914-1982
  - World War I, 1915-1918
    - Allied policy, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - Eastern Europe, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Germany, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Great Britain, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - League of Nations, 1918 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Middle East, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Naval warfare, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - Occupied France and Belgium, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - United States, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Spanish Civil War, 1936-1940
    - General, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
    - Art and culture, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Boletín al servicio de la emigración española, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Catalonian Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Embargo and neutrality issues, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - Nationalist propaganda, 1937 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Pro-Republican organizations, 1936-1939
      - American Friends of Spanish Democracy, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 2: 9)
      - International Committee of Coordination and Information to Aid Republican Spain/Comité International de Coordination et d'Information pour l'aide à l'Espagne Républicaine, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 2: 10-11)
      - International Committee of Coordination and Information to Aid Republican Spain/Comité International de Coordination et d'Information pour l'aide à l'Espagne Républicaine, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
      - National Joint Committee for Spanish Relief, 1937 (Box-folder 3: 3)
      - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 3: 4-6)
      - Washington Friends of Spanish Democracy, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 3: 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Spanish Information Bureau, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Spanish News Bulletin, 1937 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - Spanish Revolution, 1936 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Espionage case of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg and Martin Sobell, 1951-1969 (Box-folder 4: 1-5)
  - Africa, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - African Americans in Washington D.C., 1961 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - China, 1923-1966 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Civil liberties, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 4: 9-10)
  - Desegregation, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
  - East Germany, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - General Agreement on Tarrifs and Trade (GATT), 1965 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Latin America, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Persecution of the Jews in Nazi Germany, 1935 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - South-East Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO), 1964-1966 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - United States foreign policy, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - United States military, 1914-1945 (Box-folder 5: 9-10)
  - Vietnam War, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - West Germany, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
  - World peace and disarmament, 1915-1982 (Box-folder 6: 3-7)
- Miscellaneous printed matter, 1911-1937
  - Brochures, 1916-1921 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - Monographs, 1914-1937 (Box-folder 7: 3-10)
  - Report, 1918 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Serial issue, 1911 (Box-folder 7: 12)
- Photographs, 1944
  - One print depicting an aerial bomb, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - One print depicting the personnel of the 110th Evacuation Hospital, United States Army, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 14)